

DATA ANALYST

1303 Franklin Blvd, Ann Arbor, MI 48103

、 (610) 462-3868 | ☑ xilin.chen24@gmail.com | ★ xilinchen.github.io/ | ♠ xilinchen | in xilin-chen-31801b98

Summary _

Current big data analyst (aka Statistician Intermediate) at the University of Michigan, Department of Surgery. More than 3 years experience in healthcare data research and a master degree in public health. Enjoy working with complex datasets and using statistical models to solve real-world problems. Interested in finding solutions for challenging tasks, learning new technologies and tools to achieve better results, and improve team efficiency.

Experience _

Big Data Analyst Ann, Arbor, MI

University of Michigan

July 2018 - present

- Managed and analyzed multiple large data sets and created visualizations
- · Wrote reproducible code in R for data processing, data linkage, and statistical analysis
- Collaborated with a diverse team using research Sprint/Agile/Scrum

Biostatistician Pittsburgh, PA

University of Pittsburgh

Jan 2017 - July 2018

- Served as a statistical consultant and analyst for Pittsburgh Surgical Outcomes Research Center in Department of Surgery
- Assisted in manuscript writing and grand proposal preparation
- · Helped residents and primary investigators in study design, data management and analysis
- · Utilized GIS to spatially integrate databases, including geocoding, map demonstration and spatial analysis

Research Analyst Pittsburgh, PA

University of Pittsburgh

May 2016 - Jan 2017

- · Conducted data collection, evaluation, and reporting for multiple substance abuse projects in School of Pharmacy
- Designed and distributed evaluation survey, proficient with survey software (Quadratics)
- · Systematized project findings and recommendations for feasible quality improvement movements

Education

Master of Public HealthPittsburgh, PA

University of Pittsburgh

Aug 2014 - April 2016

Major: Environmental and Occupational Health

Bachelor of Science Sichuan, China

SICHUAN AGRICULTURAL UNIVERSITY

Aug 2010 - April 2014

Major: Food Science and Engineering

Skills

Programming R, Stata, SAS, Git

Analytical skills mixed model, generalizability theory, survival analysis, GEE, propensity score matching, missing data manipulation,

data linkage, generalized additive model

Database Electronic Medical Record, Claim data, clinical research data

Publication

Chen, X., Gestring, M. L., Rosengart, M. R., Billiar, T. R., Peitzman, A. B., Sperry, J. L., and Brown, J. B. (2018). Speed is not everything: Identifying patients who may benefit from helicopter transport despite faster ground transport. *Journal of trauma and acute care surgery, 84(4), 549-557.*

Chen, X., Gestring, M.L., Rosengart, M.R., Peitzman, A.B., Billiar, T.R., Sperry, J.L. and Brown, J.B., 2018. Logistics of air medical transport: When and where does helicopter transport reduce prehospital time for trauma?. *Journal of Trauma and Acute Care Surgery*, 85(1), pp.174-181.

van der Windt, D.J., Bou-Samra, P., Dadashzadeh, E.R., **Chen, X.**, Varley, P.R. and Tsung, A., 2018. Preoperative risk analysis index for frailty predicts short-term outcomes after hepatopancreatobiliary surgery. *HPB*, 20(12), pp.1181-1188.